The Farmer’s Dog Privacy Policy
===============================

Last Updated October 1, 2024.

We at The Farmer’s Dog know that you care about your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes how we use and share the information we collect when you use our website [http://www.thefarmersdog.com](https://www.thefarmersdog.com/) or otherwise interact with us.

If you are a California resident, please [click here](#your-california-privacy-rights) for more information about your privacy rights.

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, so please revisit this page to stay up to date on our privacy practices.

Types of Personal Information We Collect
----------------------------------------

When we say “Personal Information” we mean information about you that we can use to identify you.

The categories of Personal Information that we collect depend on your relationship with us, and we may disclose this Personal Information to our service providers and other third parties for the purposes described below. For example, we may collect:

* **Identifiers**, such as your name, email address, shipping address, billing address, phone number, IP Address, and User ID. We will also collect information about your pet, such as your pet’s name, medical information, and preferences. We collect this information to communicate with you, provide you with our products and services, and otherwise administer your account.
* **Information Subject to Special Protections**, such as the Identifiers above, and we or our service providers may collect your bank account number, credit card number, or debit card number. We use this information to provide you with our products and services, maintain your account, and otherwise communicate with you.
* **Characteristics of Protected Classifications under California or Federal Law**, such as race, color, ancestry, national origin, marital status, sexual orientation, gender identity, sex, pregnancy status, disability, religion, or military status. This information is collected through voluntary participation in surveys or other research activities for consumer research purposes. We use this data to better understand the diversity of our customer base and to ensure our products and services are inclusive and responsive to the needs of all communities.
* **Professional or Employment Related Information**, including details about your current or past employment, job title, employer, and employment history. This information may be gathered through surveys, questionnaires, or other interactions for consumer research purposes. The data helps us better understand the demographics and professional backgrounds of our customers, allowing us to improve and tailor our products and services to meet your needs.
* **Education Information (Non-Public under FERPA)**. We may collect non-public education information, including educational records, academic qualifications, and other details related to your academic history. This information is collected through voluntary participation in surveys or other research initiatives. We use this data for consumer research purposes to gain insights into the educational backgrounds of our customers and enhance our product offerings based on these findings.
* **Commercial Information**, such as a record of the products or services that you obtained or considered, or other information related to purchasing or consumer histories. We use this information to better understand your use of our products or services and for our internal business purposes.
* **Audio and Electronic Information**. When you call in to our customer service lines, we may record your call for quality assurances and security purposes.
* **Internet Activity Information**, such as your browsing history, search history, cookies, browser and device type, and information regarding your interactions with pages you visit on the website. We collect this information to understand your use of our website, products, and services. You can read more about our use of Cookies in our [Cookies and Other Technologies](#cookies-and-other-technologies) section below.
* **Geolocation Data**. We collect non-specific geolocation data to provide you with our products and services and to better tailor our products and services to you depending on your geographic region.
* **Profile Information**, such as information about your preferences and characteristics. We collect this information to understand your preferences and tailor our products and services and communications to you. We do not disclose this information to third parties unless we are required to do so.

Some of the information we collect may be considered **Sensitive Personal Information** under privacy laws, such as your financial information or user log in information. We use your Sensitive Personal Information only for legitimate business purposes, including to (i) perform services or provide goods reasonably expected by an average person; (ii) detect security incidents; (iii) resist malicious, deceptive, or illegal actions; (iv) ensure the physical safety of individuals; (v) for short-term, transient use; (vi) perform or provide internal business services; or (vii) verify or maintain the quality or safety of a service or device. We do not sell your Sensitive Personal Information.

We may collect Personal Information directly from you, automatically through our use of cookies and other data collection technologies on our website, and from third parties (such as friends and family that may refer you). We may also permit third party advertisers to collect information about you when you visit our website.

How We Use Personal Information
-------------------------------

In addition to the purposes for collection described above, we also collect each category of Personal Information for the purpose of maintaining our relationship with you and performing services, which include:

* Opening your account, maintaining, or servicing your account, processing, and fulfilling your requests, and other activities that are part of providing our products and services to you.
* Communicating with you regarding our products and services and other products or services that may be of interest to you.
* Developing and implementing marketing and outreach plans.
* Improving the services and products we provide to you and other consumers, including through the use of AI and other machine learning technologies which may use your Personal Information.
* Enabling service providers and contractors to provide services or products on our behalf.
* Administering and improving our website, including to measure the effectiveness of the website, to customize the content and/or layout of our website for each individual visitor, help diagnose problems with our server, see where website traffic is coming from, to identify our website users, to track our visitors’ use of the website for internal market research and to notify visitors about updates to the website or services;
* Complying with our legal, regulatory and risk management obligations, including establishing, exercising and/or defending legal claims; and
* For any other business or lawful purpose to further our relationship with you or manage our business.

How We Disclose Your Personal Information
-----------------------------------------

We may disclose your Personal Information described above with service providers who act on our behalf, our partners, to third parties at your direction, or others pursuant to a legal or internal business purpose.

* **Service Providers:** We may provide your Personal Information to our service providers that help us run and manage our business, such as technology service providers, analytics providers, customer service providers, and our credit card processors.
* **Advertising and Analytics Partners:** We may provide your Personal Information to our advertising and analytics partners to understand how you interact with our website and services. This information may be used, for example, to improve the functionality of our website and services and deliver more relevant advertisements to you.
* **As Required By Law:** We may disclose your Personal Information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process. Additionally, we may disclose Personal Information when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect the safety and security of our property or the property or others. We may also disclose Personal Information in order to protect our rights, such as to investigate fraud or respond to a government request.
* **Corporate Transaction:** In the event The Farmer’s Dog is involved in a merger, reorganization, acquisition or sale of all or a portion of its assets, or other corporate transaction, we may transfer, assign, or disclose your Personal Information as part of that transaction.
* **With your Consent:** We may disclose your Personal Information to third parties where we have received your consent for doing so.

While we have not sold Personal Information for any monetary value, our use of cookies and similar advertising technologies may be considered a “sale” under certain U.S. state consumer privacy laws. This use of tracking technologies may also be considered “sharing” under certain U.S. state consumer privacy laws. You can read more about your rights with respect to your Personal Information in the Your [California Privacy Rights](#your-california-privacy-rights) or [Other State Privacy Rights](#other-state-privacy-rights) sections below.

Cookies and Other Technologies
------------------------------

We may use “cookies” and other technologies to help us personalize and enhance your experience on our website. Our cookies and other technologies include:

* **Cookies.** A cookie is a small string of text that is sent by our website to your browser and then stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive. Our cookies allow us to personalize your experience on our website, make your visit more convenient, and understand how you and others are using our website so that we can improve your experience on the website. We use cookies to identify repeat visitors to our website and to determine the paths visitors take on our website. We also use cookies to determine whether you visited our website from a particular Internet link or advertisement. We commonly use conversion cookies to determine the number of times people who click on ads use our services or purchase products.
* **Session Replay Technology:** We use cookies that capture your interactions with our website and allow us to see your keystrokes and mouse movements when you visit our website. This service is provided through a third party. You can read more about their privacy practices at [https://www.fullstory.com/legal/privacy-policy/](https://www.fullstory.com/legal/privacy-policy/).
* **Google Analytics.** We use Google Analytics to help us understand how users engage with our services. Google Analytics uses cookies to track your interactions with our services, then collects that information and reports it to us, without identifying individual users. This information helps us improve our Services so that we can better serve users like you. For more information on Google Analytics, visit [https://Support.Google.com/Analytics](https://support.google.com/Analytics).

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but it is possible to change your browser setup so that it does not accept cookies. In order to create a profile on our website you must have your cookies on. To find out more information about cookies, visit [https://www.AllAboutCookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Browser Signals
---------------

### Do Not Track

Some web browsers have “Do Not Track” or similar features that communicate to each website you visit that you do not want your activities on that website tracked. At present, our website does not respond to “Do Not Track” signals and so our website will continue to collect information about you even if your browser’s “Do Not Track” feature is activated.

Data Security & Retention
-------------------------

We are committed to implementing safeguards designed to maintain the privacy and integrity of your Personal Information. We also rely on you for the safety and security of your information. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of the website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via digital means is not completely secure. Although we implement and maintain reasonable measures to protect your information, we cannot guarantee the security of the information transmitted to us; therefore, we do not assume any responsibility for any transmission of your information which you do at your own risk. We retain your Personal Information for as long as needed to fulfill the business purpose(s) for which we collected it. We also take into consideration the sensitivity of the data when determining its retention period.

Accessing and Modifying Your Personal Information
-------------------------------------------------

If you have registered for our services, you may be able to access, review, and make changes to information associated with your account by logging into your account and taking the desired actions. We may not be able to accommodate a request to change information if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect.

Your California Privacy Rights
------------------------------

The California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) requires us to provide specific disclosures about the Personal Information we collected in the preceding 12 months. This Privacy Policy describes the [categories of Personal Information we collect](#types-of-personal-information-we-collect) and [sources of information](#types-of-personal-information-we-collect), [to whom we disclose that information](#how-we-disclose-your-personal-information), and the [business and commercial purposes for collecting Personal Information](#how-we-use-personal-information).

In the preceding 12 months, we have disclosed your Personal Information to each of the categories of third parties [listed above](#how-we-disclose-your-personal-information) for business and commercial purposes. In addition:

* We may have sold or shared the following categories of your Personal Information with our advertising and analytics partners: Identifiers, Internet Activity Information, and Profile Information.
* We do not knowingly sell the Personal Information of users under 16 years of age.

We provide California residents the privacy rights required under applicable law, including the CCPA and Shine the Light law, as further described below.

### California Individual Privacy Rights:

* **The right to know.** You have the right to request to know what Personal Information we have collected about you, including the categories of Personal Information we have collected, the categories of sources from which we collected it, the business or commercial purpose for collecting, selling, or sharing Personal Information, the categories of third parties to whom we disclosed Personal Information, and the specific pieces of Personal Information we collected.
* **The right to correct.** You have the right to request that we correct inaccurate Personal Information that we maintain about you.
* **The right to deletion.** You have the right to request that we delete the Personal Information that we have collected or maintain about you.
* **The right to opt out of the sale or sharing of your Personal Information.** You have the right to opt out of the sale or sharing of your Personal Information. You can opt out from the collection and sharing of certain cookies as described in [Cookies and Other Technologies](#cookies-and-other-technologies) above or through the [Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information](https://preferences.thefarmersdog.com/optout) link.
* **The right to equal service.** If you choose to exercise any of these rights, we will not discriminate against you in any way. If you exercise certain rights, understand that you may be unable to use or access certain features of the Website or our Services.

If you are a California resident, you can exercise your privacy rights as described in [Submitting a Privacy Rights Request](#submitting-a-privacy-rights-request) below.

### Shine the Light:

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 gives California residents the right to request from us once per calendar year certain information regarding our disclosure of their Personal Information to third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes. You may request information regarding the disclosure of your Personal Information to third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.thefarmersdog.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Other State Privacy Rights
--------------------------

We provide residents of certain states with the privacy rights required under applicable law as further described below.

* **The right to access.** You have the right to confirm whether we are processing your Personal Information and to access such Personal Information.
* **The right to correct.** You have the right to request that we correct inaccurate Personal Information that we maintain about you. Upon receipt of a verifiable request from you, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to correct the inaccurate Personal Information.
* **The right to delete.** You have the right to request that we delete your Personal Information under specific circumstances.
* **The right to opt-out.** You have the right to object or opt out of certain types of processing, including: (1) processing for the purpose of targeted advertising, (2) processing for the purpose of the sale of Personal Information, and (3) processing for the purpose of certain types of profiling and automated decision-making.
* **The right to data portability.** You have the right to request a copy of your Personal Information in an accessible format.
* **The right to equal service.** If you choose to exercise any of these rights, we will not discriminate against you in any way. If you exercise certain rights, understand that you may be unable to use or access certain features of the website or our Services.
* **The right to appeal.** If we do not grant your consumer request, you may have the right to appeal that denial.

You can exercise your privacy rights as described in [Submitting a Privacy Rights Request](#submitting-a-privacy-rights-request) below.

Submitting a Privacy Rights Request
-----------------------------------

Depending on where you reside, you may exercise your rights free of charge (subject to limited exceptions). To exercise your rights, contact us at [(888) 814-4162](tel:+18888144162) or use our online form [here](https://preferences.thefarmersdog.com/privacy).

Where required by applicable law, we will take steps to verify your identity before processing your request. We will not fulfill your request unless you have provided sufficient information for us to reasonably verify you are the individual about whom we collected Personal Information. We may request additional information about you so that we can match the information you provide to information we already maintain about you. We will only use the Personal Information provided in the verification process to verify your identity or authority to make a request and to track and document request responses unless you initially provided the information for another purpose.

You may use an authorized agent to submit a request to know or a request to delete. When we verify your agent’s request, we may verify both your and your agent’s identity and request a signed document from you that authorizes your agent to make the request on your behalf. To protect your Personal Information, we reserve the right to deny a request from an agent that does not submit proof that they have been authorized by you to act on their behalf.

Voice Calls, Texts, and SMS messages
------------------------------------

You may have the opportunity to receive occasional voice, text, and SMS messages from us. These are typically updates on our products and services or about products and services that we think may be of interest to you. Frequency will vary. By providing your phone number and opting in to receive text messages, you expressly consent to receive these communications, including any automated text messages to the phone number that you provide. Consent to receiving text messages is not required to receive products or services from us. Message and data rates may apply, and your carrier's rates will apply. You can opt out of receiving future text messages or receive help by following the directions in the text message you receive or accessing your customer account at our website. As we are in the United States, international rates may apply depending on your location. We may disclose your mobile phone number to service providers with whom we contract to send you automated text messages. However, we will not disclose your mobile phone number to third parties for their own marketing purposes without your express consent. We may still contact you about your account even if you opt out of calls, texts, or SMS.

Email Consent and Opt-Out
-------------------------

If you do not wish to have your email address used by us to promote our products or services, you can opt-out by managing your communication preferences in your customer account at our website or by clicking the unsubscribe link contained within any promotional email you received. This opt-out does not apply to transactional or relationship email messages we may send.

Persons Under 16 Years of Age
-----------------------------

Our website is not intended for or directed to persons under 16 years of age. We do not knowingly collect or maintain information on our website from those we know are under 16, and we do not permit persons under 16 years of age to become registered users of our website. If we become aware that we have collected information from an individual under 16 years of age, we will immediately delete such information.

Links To Third-Party Web Sites
------------------------------

Our website may offer links to other websites which may have information policies and practices different from ours. We do not control and are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices or the content of any third party websites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of any third party website prior to providing them with your Personal Information.

Changes to the Privacy Policy
-----------------------------

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices. When we post modifications to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the “Last Updated” date at the top of this web page. If the changes are material, we will endeavor to notify you in advance of such changes taking place. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Non-U.S. Residents
------------------

The website is intended for use in the United States only. If you visit our website or contact us from outside of the United States, please be advised that (1) any information you provide to us or that we automatically collect will be transferred to the United States; and (2) that by using our website or submitting information, you explicitly authorize its transfer to and subsequent processing in the United States in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Do not provide your Personal Information to us if you do not want this information to be transferred outside of your country, or if the laws in your country restrict these types of transfers. We will treat your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

How To Contact Us
-----------------

If you have questions or comments about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.thefarmersdog.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

#### Site Map

* [Careers](https://www.thefarmersdog.com/careers)We're Hiring!

#### ContactAvailable 24/7

[\[email protected\]](https://www.thefarmersdog.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)[Instagram](https://instagram.com/thefarmersdog)[Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/thefarmersdog)[\[email protected\]](https://www.thefarmersdog.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)[Partnership Inquiries](https://thefarmersdog.typeform.com/workwithus)

#### Free Health and Nutrition Tips

Email

Submit

Our food is made while playing doo-wop tunes, all with ❤ in the US

© 2024 The Farmer’s Dog, Inc.  
Long Live Dogs™

Open Chat
